fiat.com 2015-10-06

# Privacy

#### General introduction

This Policy is intended to describe the management of this website owned by Fiat Group Automobiles S.p.A., in relation to the processing of this website’s users/visitors personal data.  
Fiat Group Automobiles S.p.A., in line with the current Italian data protection law, undertakes to guarantee the privacy and the security of each website navigator's personal data, even when the Internet is accessed from abroad, consistently with the requirements of the Fiat Group S.p.A. Code of Conduct.  
The Policy is also given as a short Information, if a specific detailed one is not provided, pursuant to Section 13 of Legislative Decree 196/03 – Personal Data Protection Code, issued in application of Art. 10 and 11 from European Directive 95/46/CE, to those who interact with the website services, with the purpose of protecting personal data accessible by computer.  
Detailed information regarding processing, as per Section 13 of Legislative Decree 196/03 – Personal Data Protection Code - is provided, where necessary, in the pages where services are offered. These Information aim to define the data processing limits and procedures for each service so that the customer/visitor may freely provide consent and authorise collection of his/her personal data and its subsequent use.  
Please note that the Information will not be provided for other websites possibly accessed by the user through links.

#### DATA CONTROLLER, DATA PROCESSOR AND PERSONS IN CHARGE OF THE PROCESSING

The Data Controller is the presiding head of the Information & Communication Technologies department of Fiat Group Automobiles S.p.A., with registered office in Turin, Corso Agnelli 200, Italy. The Data Processor for this Service is the presiding head of Commercial Operations of Fiat Group Automobiles S.p.A..  
The personal data that you have provided may be handled by Data Processing Officers, including external, responsible for managing the requested service and by Data Processor(s).

#### TYPE OF DATA PROCESSED AND PURPOSE OF PROCESSING

This website offers informative and interactive content. During website navigation, information regarding the customer, or more generally regarding the visitor to the site, may be acquired as follows: **  
Navigation Data**  
During normal operation, the IT systems and software procedures used to run this site collect some personal data, which are implicitly transmitted through the use of Internet communication protocols.  
This information is not collected in order to be associated with identified data subjects, but could, due to their own nature, and if processed and integrated with third-party data, allow Users to be identified.  
IP addresses, browser type, operating system, domain name and website referring or exit pages, information on pages visited by the User within the site, access time, navigation length on each page, clickstream analysis and other parameters regarding the operating system and the user IT environment, all fall under this category of data.  
This technical/IT data are collected and used on an aggregated and anonymous basis exclusively to improve quality of service and obtain statistics on website use.  
These technical data are collected and used in an aggregated and anonymous way for the sole purpose of:  
1\. improving the quality of the service and optimize the functionality of the website;   
2\. understanding user behavior in order to improve online communication;  
3\. providing statistical information concerning the use of the website.

**GEOGRAPHICAL LOCATION DATA**  
Upon previous consent of the user, the website may process geographical location data - in a discontinuous way - to provide the services that user has requested.

 **DATA VOLUNTARILY SUPPLIED BY THE CUSTOMER/VISITOR**  
These cases involve the customer/visitor entering his/her personal data on the website after reading detailed information in order to access personally selected services.   
"Opt-in" and "Opt-out" policies: in all cases, appropriate detailed information is provided and, where required, consent for the processing of personal data is obtained before a given service is activated. Said consent may be revoked at any time, whereby the ability to use the service in question is lost.  
Specific information is gradually provided or displayed on pages of the website that offer specific services on request. **  
Data from Minors**  
Fiat Group Automobiles S.p.A. does not allow minors under 18 years of age to supply personal data.

#### DATA PROCESSING RULES

The data processing will be performed through automated means (ie. using electronic procedures) and/or manually (ie. on paper) for the time necessary to achieve the purposes for which the data were collected and in compliance with current data protection law.

#### Technologies

**Cookies**  
Cookies (1) are not used for the transmission of personal information.  
The use of session cookies (which are not permanently stored on the user's computer and disappear when the browser is closed) is strictly limited to transmitting session identifiers required to enable a safe and efficient website navigation.  
Session cookies used on this website avoid the use of other technologies that could potentially compromise the privacy of the users navigation and do not allow the acquisition of personal identification data.  
This website also uses persistent cookies, i.e. cookies that are stored on the computer hard disk until their expiration or cancellation by the users/visitors. The deletion of cookies does not preclude the use of websites.   
Through persistent cookies users/visitors to the site (or any other user that use the same computer) are automatically recognized at each visit.  
The user/visitor may set the computer browser in order to accept/refuse all cookies or receive a notice  each time a cookie is proposed, in order to decide whether to accept it or not (2). **  
Javascript**  
This is a technique used as an alternative to direct analysis of Web server log files. It consists of collecting and processing navigation data using dedicated JavaScript code in the HTML pages deemed of interest.

#### External services

**Sophus**  
This website uses the external Web analysis service provided by SOPHUS, which uses javascript technology to allow the website to analyze how Users use this website. The information regarding the use of the website by the user (including his/her IP address) will be sent and stored on SOPHUS servers (UK). SOPHUS will use this information to track and examine the use of the website, to create reports on website activities for the website operators, and to provide other services related to website activities and to the use of Internet. SOPHUS may also transfer this information to third parties where required by law or when these third parties process the abovementioned information on behalf of SOPHUS. SOPHUS will not associate your IP address with any other data owned by SOPHUS. By using this website, the User consents to the processing of his/her personal data by SOPHUS for the abovementioned purposes and procedures.  
**Google Analytics**  
This website uses the external Web analysis service provided by Google Analytics, which uses javascript technology to allow the website to analyze how users use this website. The information regarding the use of the website by the user (including his/her IP address) will be sent and stored on Google Analytics servers. Google Analytics will use this information to track and examine use of the website, to create reports on site activities for the website operators, and to provide other services related to website activities and to the use of the Internet. Google Analytics may also transfer this information to third parties where required by law or when these third parties process the abovementioned information on behalf of Google Analytics. Google Analytics will not associate your IP address with any other data owned by Google Analytics. By using this website, the User consents to the processing of his/her personal data by Google Analytics for the abovementioned purposes and procedures.

#### Connection to sites of third parties

It is possible to link to other websites from this website; the ability to do so is clearly indicated in order to inform the user/visitor that he/she is leaving the Fiat Group Automobiles S.p.A. website.  
The user/visitor should note that these websites are not the property or responsibility of Fiat Group Automobiles S.p.A. as they are fully managed by other companies and/or organizations. It is therefore necessary to verify and accept their data protection policies.  
Fiat Group Automobiles S.p.A. consequently declines all responsibility for requests and/or release of personal data to third-party sites.

#### DATA SUBJECT’S RIGHTS

The data subject has the right at any time to obtain confirmation of the existence of the data and to know its contents and origin, to check its accuracy or request integration, updating or correction (Art. 7 of Legislative Decree 196/03).  
Pursuant to this Section the data subject has the right to request the complete and updated list of all the data processors, to request cancellation, anonimyzation or blocking of data that have been processed unlawfully and may refuse, for legitimate reasons, their processing.

To exercise these rights and in case of any problem or further requests for clarification related to what above mentioned, please write to Fiat Group Automobiles S.p.A. - Customer Experience & CRM - Data Protection Office - C.so Agnelli 200 - 10135 Torino.

#### POLICY CHANGES

This Privacy Policy governs the methods for processing personal data provided by customers/visitors when navigating our website. These methods may need to be modified as a result of new laws entering into force or after examination and updating of User services. As a result, our policy may be modified over time, and we kindly ask customers/visitors to periodically consult this page.

1) Cookies are pieces of information that are sent by a web server (ie. the website) to the user’s Internet browser. The browser automatically saves the information on the computer and automatically sends it to the server each time the website is accessed.

2) By default, almost all web browsers are set to automatically accept cookies. You can always change the default configuration, that with browser like, for example, Internet Explorer version 6.0 is the average, and disable cookies (i.e. block them permanently), by setting in the specific tab ("Privacy"), the highest level of protection (very high), but we inform you that by disabling such functions the use of the Service can be compromised. In any case, you can also cancel (or delete) cookies from your personal computer , by selecting, on "Internet Options" from Tools menu, the "General" tab and clicking on the Delete Cookies button.

14 December 2012.
